

CONTACT INFO

- Bangalore, India
- arun.srinivasan@outlook.in
- +91 81237 61771
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/c4arun/
- https://srinivasan-arun.github.io/cv/

SKILLS SUMMARY

Engineering Management

Software Development

Process Improvement

Resource Planning

Tech Designs

Microservices

Event-Driven Architecture

Cloud

- AWS
- GCP

DevOps

- Jenkins
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- ELK
- App Monitoring Tools

Full Stack Web Development

- Java/JEE
- Spring Boot
- Vert.X
- PWA
- NodeJS
- Elastic Search
- MySQL, MongoDB
- Apache Kafka
- Redis

Tools

- JIRA
- Git
- Confluence
- Bitbucket

ARUN SRINIVASAN

TECH MANAGER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Tech Manager having 9 years of experience in web-based development. I am responsible for software design, assisting the team with technology/framework selection, actively remove obstacles, and drive towards engineering excellence by implementing and improving processes around DevOps, Agile and work with the product management team to align engineering readiness for upcoming business requirements. I am also well versed in microservices and event-driven architecture.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tech Manager

BetterPlace | Apr 2019 - present

- Bootstrapped the Platform 2.0 approach for all products with the aim to move towards a SaaS-based business model.
- Conduct day-to-day project coordination, planning, and implementation across multiple teams
- Translated requirements into polished, high-level designs
- Implemented and improved processes around DevOps, Agile and ensured high-quality product delivery within the given timeline.
- Coach, manage and mentor a team of Engineers.

Application Team Lead

Unisys India | Jul 2012 - Mar 2019

- Worked on many complex projects from start to finish in Public sector and Transportation Domain
- Hands-on experience in implementing IoT-based solution (including hardware design) for a Pharmaceutical domain project.
- Hands-on experience on complex Java/JEE, NodeJS based web development

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Coimbatore Institute of Technology, Anna University

B.E in Computer Science | Jun 2008 - Apr 2012

• CGPA 8.56

S.K.V Higher Secondary School, TamilNadu

Higher Secondary Education | Jun 2006 - Apr 2008

• Percentage - 95%